# SRIRAM KARTHIK AKELLA

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Edmonton Canada

#### PHONE

+1 (825) 461 4747

#### **EMAIL**

sk.akella7@gmail.com

#### LINKS

**Portfolio** 

**Linkedin** 

<u>Github</u>

#### SKILLS

Agile Methodology

Git

Python

Java

Dart

SQL

Microsoft Office

Flutter

#### PROFILE

I am currently enrolled in the **Science Internship Program (co-op)** at my university, which allows me to work full-time for 4, 8, 12 or 16 months. My role in the team I currently work at is to automate networking operations. My main interest lies in the field of Software Development and I am looking forward to getting this experience in my next co-op term. I believe that I have the ability to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## **Network Analyst Student, City of Edmonton**

Edmonton, Canada

Jan 2023 — Present

I am currently doing a co-op term at the City of Edmonton's Network Enterprise Team. My main role in the team is to automate networking operations. I also assist the team in analyzing network requirements and configuring computer hardware and software for optimal network communication.

# **Undergraduate Teaching Assistant, University of Alberta**

Edmonton, Canada

Jan 2022 — Jun 2022

TAing CMPUT 175 - Introduction to the Foundations of Computation II.

- Conducted lab sessions every week and assisted students in one on one and small group setting.
- Assisted teaching staff in designing the course.

## **Academic Tutor, UAlberta Student Union**

Edmonton, Canada

Nov 2021

Tutoring students in CMPUT, MATH & STAT classes.

# **Information Technology Intern, Kuwait Oil Company** Al Ahmadi, Kuwait Jul 2019 — Aug 2019

I have worked as an IT Intern at Kuwait Oil Company receiving practical knowledge on Database and Server Hardware, Cloud Computing, ITIL and ISO Standards, Operating Systems & Computer Networks. For a term of one week, I had also assisted at the Service Desk of the IT Department of Diyar United Company to help clients

## EDUCATION

## **Bachelor of Science, University of Alberta**

Edmonton, Canada

Sep 2020 — 2024

Specialization in Computing Science

by troubleshooting their IT-related issues.

## Specialization in Algorithms, Stanford University

Remote

Jan 2023

Studied the fundamental principles of algorithm design.

#### **SELECTED PROJECTS**

## The Smart Eye

2019

Created an assistive device for the visually impaired people called 'The Smart Eye' which can reduce their dependence on others in terms of mobility. The device uses ML & Al to detect and recognize objects in the field of view of the user.

## Qify Virtual Clinic - KFAS Virtual Hackathon

2020

Created a 'virtual clinic' mobile application for Android and iOS (using Flutter and Firebase) for our participation in the KFAS & CODED Virtual Hackathon - Emergency Resilience.

The main goal of the project was to eliminate the pressure created on medical systems during the COVID-19 pandemic by creating digital queues for consulting the doctor. This would help in resolving the mild cases over a video call and bringing serious ones to the hospital.

#### COURSES

## Crash Course on Python, Google

Oct 2020

## Python Data Structures, University of Michigan

Nov 2020

## **Abacus Graduate, UCMAS**

Jul 2009 — Jul 2014

## Web Designing & Photoshop, Softworld

Jun 2016

#### CLUBS

## **Undergraduate Association of Computing Science**

Edmonton, Canada

Jan 2022 — Present

Junior Representative

## **Google Developer Student Club**

Edmonton, Canada

Apr 2021 — Present

Campus Member

# REFERENCES

## References available upon request